export const cluster_4_rad_phato = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "Biopsy of a tumor will allow physicians to identify the disease and therefore have?",
    options: ["prognosis", "sequelae", "diagnosis", "Signs"],
    correctAnswer: "diagnosis", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "Identification of the disease through biopsy allows for diagnosis.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is the most common cause of acute cholecystitis?",
    options: [
      "obstruction of the cystic duct by an impacted cholelith",
      "damage of the gallbladder mucosa due to stones",
      "chronic alcohol abuse",
      "fatty diet",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "obstruction of the cystic duct by an impacted cholelith", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is transmitted via feco-oral route?",
    options: ["HDV", "HCV", "HBV", "HAV"],
    correctAnswer: "HAV", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "This malignant tumor usually occurs between the ages of 5-15 years old and often involves the entire shaft of a long bone.",
    options: ["Chondrosarcoma", "Ewing sarcoma", "osteosarcoma", "Osteoma"],
    correctAnswer: "Ewing sarcoma", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "What is the usual radiographic appearance of achalasia?",
    options: ["wavy border", "jet smoke", "rat-tail appearance", "Tubular"],
    correctAnswer: "rat-tail appearance", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "Which condition is seen in plain radiographs as gas in the gallbladder lumen which dissects into the wall or pericholecystic tissues?",
    options: ["acute cholecystitis", "chronic cholecystitis", "pancreatitis", "emphysematous cholecystitis"],
    correctAnswer: "emphysematous cholecystitis", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Which of the following conditions would probably affect the skeletal system the most?",
    options: ["Cushing syndrome", "Addison disease", "hyperparathyroidism", "papillary thyroid carcinoma"],
    correctAnswer: "hyperparathyroidism", // 'c' = 2
    rationale:
      "Cushing syndrome - makes too much of the hormone cortisol over a long period of time. Addison disease - kulang sa cortisol (very weak)",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "What condition is present when there is loss of elasticity in the lungs?",
    options: ["asthma", "Anthrax", "emphysema", "Anthracosis"],
    correctAnswer: "emphysema", // 'c' = 2
    rationale:
      "Anthrax - a serious disease usually caused by Bacillus anthracis bacteria, Anthracosis - inhalation of small particles of coal dust over a long period of Time.",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "Which condition refers to the failure of the fingers or toes to separate and causes the physical appearance of webbed digits?",
    options: ["Polydactyly", "syndactyly", "craniotubular dysplasia", "osteogenesis imperfecta"],
    correctAnswer: "syndactyly", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "Which of the following modalities are used with conventional x-rays when performing radiographic investigation of the gastrointestinal system?",
    options: ["fluoroscopy", "sonography", "computed tomography", "MRI"],
    correctAnswer: "fluoroscopy", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "Which of the following is most commonly caused by influenza virus?",
    options: ["interstitial pneumonia", "lobar pneumonia", "aspiration pneumonia", "segmental pneumonia"],
    correctAnswer: "interstitial pneumonia", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "What is the usual appearance of tuberculosis of the bone?",
    options: ["hair-on-end", "string sign", "ground-glass", "Worm-eaten"],
    correctAnswer: "Worm-eaten", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "Gastric atrophy is associated with which type of anemia?",
    options: ["myelophthisic anemia", "megaloblastic anemia", "sickle cell anemia", "aplastic anemia"],
    correctAnswer: "megaloblastic anemia", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "Which of the following is a nuclear medicine procedure for the evaluation of the gallbladder?",
    options: ["Cholescintigraphy", "131I Uptake", "Bone Scintigraphy", "MRCP"],
    correctAnswer: "Cholescintigraphy", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "Overinflated lung is medically termed as:",
    options: ["atelectasis", "asthma", "emphysema", "chronic obstructive pulmonary disease"],
    correctAnswer: "emphysema", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "What is the pattern of inheritance of achondroplasia?",
    options: ["autosomal recessive", "x-linked recessive", "x-linked dominant", "autosomal dominant"],
    correctAnswer: "autosomal dominant", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: "Which of the following is the malignant neoplasm of smooth muscles?",
    options: ["Leiomyoma", "Rhabdomyoma", "leiomyosarcoma", "Rhabdomyosarcoma"],
    correctAnswer: "leiomyosarcoma", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "Osteoporosis decreases bone density. This is an example of which type of disease?",
    options: ["additive disease", "neoplastic disease", "acute disease", "subtractive disease"],
    correctAnswer: "subtractive disease", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question:
      "This is the functional obstruction of the distal section of the esophagus with proximal dilation caused by incomplete relaxation of the lower sphincter.",
    options: ["Achalasia", "hiatal hernia", "tracheoesophageal fistula", "esophageal obstruction"],
    correctAnswer: "Achalasia", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "What is the term for the process that ultimately leads to manifestations of the disease?",
    options: ["Pathogenesis", "Disease", "Diagnosis", "Prognosis"],
    correctAnswer: "Pathogenesis", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "This condition of the pancreas is reversible and often results from biliary tract diseases.",
    options: ["chronic pancreatitis", "jaundice", "acute pancreatitis", "pancreatic carcinoma"],
    correctAnswer: "acute pancreatitis", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: "What is the most common etiologic agent of osteomyelitis in infants?",
    options: ["S. aureus", "H. pylori", "S. pyogenes", "E. coli"],
    correctAnswer: "E. coli", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: "What is the most common primary malignant lung neoplasm?",
    options: ["bronchogenic carcinoma", "bronchial carcinoid tumor", "pleural effusion", "metastasis of the lungs"],
    correctAnswer: "bronchogenic carcinoma", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "Which of the following can be used in the investigation of GI bleed?",
    options: ["Tc-99m DTPA", "Tc-99m-labeled RBCs", "Tc-99m HMPAO", "Tc=99m diphosphonates"],
    correctAnswer: "Tc-99m-labeled RBCs", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: "Which etiologic agent commonly causes chronic gastritis?",
    options: ["H. pylori", "E. coli", "amoeba", "HBV"],
    correctAnswer: "H. pylori", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "Which of the following pathologies of the endocrine system can be examined using plain radiography?",
    options: ["Graves disease", "Cushing syndrome", "Addison disease", "osteoporosis"],
    correctAnswer: "osteoporosis", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "Which type of tuberculosis is traditionally considered a disease for children and young adults?",
    options: ["primary tuberculosis", "secondary tuberculosis", "tuberculoma", "Pott’s disease"],
    correctAnswer: "primary tuberculosis", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: "Which of the following lead to atrial septal defect?",
    options: [
      "fistula between the left and right atrium",
      "improper closure of the ductus ateriosus",
      "improper closure of the foramen ovale",
      "interventricular septum defect",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "fistula between the left and right atrium", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: "Oxygen levels in the arteries that are lower than normal is termed as?",
    options: ["Hypercapnia", "hypoxemia", "hyperemia", "Hypoxia"],
    correctAnswer: "hypoxemia", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: "What would most likely happen to dusts that are 3um in diameter?",
    options: ["filtered out", "remain suspended in the air", "trapped in the lungs", "exhaled with CO2"],
    correctAnswer: "trapped in the lungs", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: "Which of the following group of brittle bone disease is present at birth?",
    options: [
      "osteogenesis imperfecta tarda",
      "none of the choices",
      "both choices",
      "osteogenesis imperfecta congenita",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "osteogenesis imperfecta congenita", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: "What is the imaging appearance of gallstones with fissures that are filled with air?",
    options: ["ground glass appearance", "air-fluid level", "tram lines", "Mercedes-Benz sign"],
    correctAnswer: "Mercedes-Benz sign", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question:
      "This is a chronic inflammatory disorder of unknown cause that most often involves the terminal area of the ileum.",
    options: ["small bowel obstruction", "adynamic ileus", "Crohn’s disease", "intussusception"],
    correctAnswer: "Crohn’s disease", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question:
      "This cellular adaptation involves conversion of one cell type into another cell type that is not normal for that tissue.",
    options: ["Dysplasia", "metaplasia", "hyperplasia", "Atrophy"],
    correctAnswer: "metaplasia", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: "Medullary tumors of the adrenal gland is imaged in nuclear medicine using which radiopharmaceutical?",
    options: [
      "Iodine-131 metaiodobenzylguanidine",
      "Iodine-123",
      "Technetium-99 diphosphonate",
      "Technetium-99 SESTAMIBI",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Iodine-131 metaiodobenzylguanidine", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: "Coal miners are prone to which condition?",
    options: ["asbestosis", "silicosis", "COPD", "Anthracosis"],
    correctAnswer: "Anthracosis", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question:
      "Which of the following disorder involves antibodies that destroy TSH receptors, causing the thyroid gland to secrete excessive amount of hormones?",
    options: ["Goiter", "Hashimoto thyroiditis", "Hyperparathyroidism", "Graves disease"],
    correctAnswer: "Graves disease", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "What is the composition of majority of the stones in the gallbladder?",
    options: [
      "Pure cholesterol",
      "Mixture of cholesterol, bile pigment and calcium salts",
      "Pure calcium salts",
      "Mixture of calcium and bilirubin",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mixture of cholesterol, bile pigment and calcium salts", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: "Dilation of the blood vessel that involves its entire diameter is termed as?",
    options: ["fusiform aneurysm", "berry aneurysm", "saccular aneurysm", "corpuscular aneurysm"],
    correctAnswer: "fusiform aneurysm", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "Which of the following is common radiographic appearance of Hyaline Membrane Disease?",
    options: ["Tram lines", "Dirty chest", "Ground glass", "Coin lesion"],
    correctAnswer: "Ground glass", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question:
      "This is commonly a unilateral, benign solid tumor in the breast that does not invade surrounding tissues:",
    options: ["ductal carcinoma in situ", "lobular carcinoma in situ", "mastitis", "fibroadenoma"],
    correctAnswer: "fibroadenoma", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: "These are the most common benign tumors of the female reproductive system:",
    options: ["uterine fibroids", "endometriosis", "hydatidiform mole", "fibroadenoma"],
    correctAnswer: "uterine fibroids", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question: "Too little amniotic fluid is termed as:",
    options: ["Polyhydramnios", "oligohydramnios", "normohydramnios", "Potter syndrome"],
    correctAnswer: "oligohydramnios", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: "All left-to-right shunts lead to which type of increased pulmonary blood pressure?",
    options: ["Eisenmenger’s Syndrome", "congestive heart failure", "Eisenmeyer hypertension", "pulmonary edema"],
    correctAnswer: "Eisenmenger’s Syndrome", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: "This is the most common type of germ cell tumor:",
    options: ["choriocarcinoma", "dermoid cysts", "PCOS", "fibroadenoma"],
    correctAnswer: "dermoid cysts", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question: "What is the most common abnormality in the upper gastrointestinal system?",
    options: ["esophagitis", "hiatal hernia", "diverticula", "GERD"],
    correctAnswer: "hiatal hernia", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question:
      "Urinary tract infection due to catheter insertion in a patient with urethral obstruction is classified as?",
    options: ["Iatrogenic", "Asymptomatic", "Idiopathic", "Pathologic"],
    correctAnswer: "Iatrogenic", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question:
      "Your patient is diagnosed with a neoplastic proliferation of white blood cells. It was noted that he has increased number of granulocytes and decreased production of red blood cells and thrombocytes. What is the disease entity?",
    options: ["lymphocytic leukemia", "pancytopenia", "polycythemia", "myelocytic leukemia"],
    correctAnswer: "myelocytic leukemia", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question: "What type of metastasis happens when the neoplasm extends directly to other directions?",
    options: ["local invasion", "hematogenous metastases", "lymphogenous metastases", "bronchogenic metastases"],
    correctAnswer: "local invasion", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question: "This condition involves the reflux of stomach contents into the esophagus.",
    options: ["GERD", "hiatal hernia", "diverticulosis", "Volvulus"],
    correctAnswer: "GERD", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    question: "Which hormone is secreted in excess in acromegaly?",
    options: ["thyroid hormones", "growth hormone", "calcitonin", "cortisol"],
    correctAnswer: "growth hormone", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    question: "Which segment of the colon is most prone to diverticulosis?",
    options: ["sigmoid colon", "transverse colon", "ascending colon", "descending colon"],
    correctAnswer: "sigmoid colon", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    question: "Retention of urea in the blood is termed as:",
    options: ["Azotemia", "uremia", "proteinuria", "hematuria"],
    correctAnswer: "uremia", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    question:
      "Which of the following is the modality of choice for detection and staging of soft tissue tumors in the extremities?",
    options: ["CT", "MRI", "Radiography", "Sonography"],
    correctAnswer: "MRI", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    question: "What is the oldest and most serious type of pneumoconiosis?",
    options: ["Anthracosis", "Asbestosis", "silicosis", "Pneumonoultramicroscopicsilicovulcanoconiosis"],
    correctAnswer: "silicosis", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 56,
    question: "This is the condition wherein one of the kidneys failed to form.",
    options: ["Unilateral renal agenesis", "Supernumerary kidneys", "Horseshoe kidney", "Ectopic Kidney"],
    correctAnswer: "Unilateral renal agenesis", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    question: "This condition involves calcification of plaques along the wall of the arteries.",
    options: ["arthritis", "hypertension", "coronary artery disease", "Atherosclerosis"],
    correctAnswer: "Atherosclerosis", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    question: "Which procedure is useful in the differential diagnosis between medical and surgical jaundice?",
    options: [
      "Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangiopancreatogram",
      "Operative Cholangiography",
      "T-tube Cholangiography",
      "Percutaneous Transhepatic Cholangiography",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Percutaneous Transhepatic Cholangiography", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    question: "Osteomalacia in infants and children is known as?",
    options: ["Rickets", "chondromalacia", "Scurvy", "Anemia"],
    correctAnswer: "Rickets", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 60,
    question: "This is the most common modality utilized when suspected appendicitis is to be evaluated.",
    options: ["sonography", "CT", "MRI", "nuclear medicine procedures"],
    correctAnswer: "sonography", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 61,
    question: "Collapse of the whole or some parts of the lungs is termed as?",
    options: ["atelectasis", "asthma", "emphysema", "COPD"],
    correctAnswer: "atelectasis", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 62,
    question: "Diseases that are transmitted from a parent to offspring is called?",
    options: ["Congenital", "metabolic", "neoplastic", "Hereditary"],
    correctAnswer: "Hereditary", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 63,
    question: "Which of the following is a characteristic of Type 2 DM?",
    options: [
      "the cells are insensitive to insulin",
      "it is an autoimmune disease",
      "it is independent of lifestyle",
      "it typically presents at younger age",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "the cells are insensitive to insulin", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 64,
    question: "This refers to the insufficient mineralization of the adult skeleton.",
    options: ["osteomalacia", "chondromalacia", "Rickets", "Osteopetrosis"],
    correctAnswer: "osteomalacia", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 65,
    question: "Which type of jaundice is due to an obstruction?",
    options: ["surgical", "medical", "congenital", "neoplastic"],
    correctAnswer: "surgical", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 66,
    question: "Which scanner is specific for the imaging of the heart?",
    options: [
      "multidetector scanner",
      "helical computed tomography scanner",
      "electron beam computed tomography scanner",
      "spiral computed tomography scanner",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "electron beam computed tomography scanner", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 67,
    question: "Which of the following most likely has the best prognosis?",
    options: [
      "moderately differentiated squamous cell carcinoma",
      "undifferentiated large cell carcinoma",
      "well-differentiated ductal carcinoma in situ",
      "undifferentiated basal cell carcinoma",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "well-differentiated ductal carcinoma in situ", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 68,
    question: "Which condition is due to the incomplete maturation of type II alveolar cells?",
    options: ["Atelectasis", "Bronchiectasis", "Respiratory distress syndrome", "respiratory failure"],
    correctAnswer: "Respiratory distress syndrome", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 69,
    question:
      "Severe GERD will result in the change of the lining of the esophagus from squamous epithelium to columnar epithelium. This is known as:",
    options: ["esophageal cancer", "Barrett’s esophagus", "tracheoesophageal fistula", "Reflux"],
    correctAnswer: "Barrett’s esophagus", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 70,
    question: "What is the most frequent early response to alcohol abuse?",
    options: ["fatty liver", "viral hepatitis", "cirrhosis", "NAFLD"],
    correctAnswer: "fatty liver", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 71,
    question:
      "Which of the following pneumonia will most likely be due to irregularly cleaned air conditioning systems?",
    options: ["Cystic fibrosis", "lobar pneumonia", "Legionnaires’ disease", "interstitial pneumonia"],
    correctAnswer: "Legionnaires’ disease", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 72,
    question: "What is the term for the premature separation of the placenta from the uterus?",
    options: ["placental percreta", "placenta previa", "placental abruptio", "placental necrosis"],
    correctAnswer: "placental abruptio", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 73,
    question: "This is the term for the deposition of calcium in the renal parenchyma:",
    options: ["urinary calculi", "nephrocalcinosis", "staghorn calculi", "osteoporosis"],
    correctAnswer: "nephrocalcinosis", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 74,
    question: "What is the classification of polydactyly?",
    options: ["congenital", "hereditary", "metabolic", "Neoplastic"],
    correctAnswer: "congenital", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 75,
    question: "Which of the following is best for detection of bone metastases?",
    options: ["Nuclear medicine procedures", "radiography", "sonography", "MRI"],
    correctAnswer: "Nuclear medicine procedures", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 76,
    question: "Which of the following is the least aggressive thyroid malignancy?",
    options: ["papillary", "follicular", "medullary", "undifferentiated anaplastic"],
    correctAnswer: "papillary", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 77,
    question: "Which part of the spinal cord is most commonly affected in spina bifida?",
    options: ["lumbar", "cervical", "thoracic", "sacral"],
    correctAnswer: "lumbar", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 78,
    question: "This is almost always a complication of rheumatic heart disease and involves thickening of the valve.",
    options: ["coronary artery disease", "congestive heart failure", "hypertension", "mitral stenosis"],
    correctAnswer: "mitral stenosis", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 79,
    question: "What is the usual appearance of bronchiectasis in a radiograph?",
    options: ["tram lines", "ruffled feathers", "ground glass", "dirty chest"],
    correctAnswer: "tram lines", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 80,
    question: "This is the acute inflammation of the pia and arachnoid mater:",
    options: ["hydrocephalus", "meningitis", "encephalitis", "cerebral infarction"],
    correctAnswer: "meningitis", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 81,
    question: "What is the term for undescended testes?",
    options: ["benign prostatic hyperplasia", "testicular seminomas", "testicular teratomas", "cryptorchidism"],
    correctAnswer: "cryptorchidism", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 82,
    question: "Which of the following is a large calculi that assumes the shape of the pelvicalyceal junction?",
    options: ["Horseshoe calculus", "Nephrocalcinosis", "Staghorn calculus", "none of the choices is correct"],
    correctAnswer: "Staghorn calculus", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 83,
    question: "How will you adjust technical factors in respiratory conditions that add fluid to the lungs?",
    options: [
      "decrease technical factors",
      "use normal technical factors",
      "increase technical factors",
      "do not adjust technical factors but make adjustments in post-processing",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "increase technical factors", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 84,
    question: "The term atherothrombotic brain infarction denotes:",
    options: [
      "Brain hemorrhage caused by atherosclerosis",
      "Infarction caused by thrombosis of a cerebral artery",
      "An embolism to the brain from a left heart thrombus",
      "None of the choices",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Infarction caused by thrombosis of a cerebral artery", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 85,
    question:
      "Narrowing of the coronary arteries that may be due to hypertension, obesity, smoking, high-cholesterol diet, or lack of exercise is generally termed as?",
    options: [
      "congestive heart failure",
      "coronary artery disease",
      "coarctation of the aorta",
      "myocardial infarction",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "coronary artery disease", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 86,
    question: "Which of the following is a symptom?",
    options: ["Fever", "Nausea", "high blood pressure", "Rashes"],
    correctAnswer: "Nausea", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 87,
    question: "Which condition manifests in the image as a linitis plastica pattern?",
    options: ["esophageal cancer", "intestinal cancer", "colon cancer", "stomach cancer"],
    correctAnswer: "stomach cancer", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 88,
    question: "This is the presence of endometrial tissue or glands outside the uterus in abnormal locations:",
    options: ["leiomyomas", "teratomas", "endometriosis", "PCOS"],
    correctAnswer: "endometriosis", // 'c' = 2
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 89,
    question:
      "Which variant of rheumatoid arthritis has predilection to young males and is associated with bacterial infections of the GI and genitourinary systems?",
    options: ["Reiter syndrome", "Psoriatic arthritis", "tuberculosis", "ankylosing spondylitis"],
    correctAnswer: "Reiter syndrome", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 90,
    question:
      "Which of the following neoplastic conditions is highly malignant and often occurs in the cerebellum of children?",
    options: ["Astrocytoma", "Medulloblastoma", "Meningioma", "Pituitary adenoma"],
    correctAnswer: "Medulloblastoma", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 91,
    question: "Which of the following is a classic appearance of Tetralogy of Fallot?",
    options: ["Coeur en sabot appearance", "rib notching", "figure-3 sign", "reverse figure-3 sign"],
    correctAnswer: "Coeur en sabot appearance", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 92,
    question: "What is the common etiologic agent of infectious mononucleosis?",
    options: ["herpes simplex virus", "Epstein-Barr virus", "cytomegalovirus", "influenza virus"],
    correctAnswer: "Epstein-Barr virus", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 93,
    question: "Which of the following structure helps in making KUB visible radiographically?",
    options: [
      "fluid content of the kidneys",
      "perirenal fat capsule",
      "calcium that is normally in the kidney parenchyma",
      "bowel content",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "perirenal fat capsule", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 94,
    question: "Which of the following is indicative of respiratory failure?",
    options: ["PO2 50; PCO2 60", "PO2 65; PCO2 40", "PO2 65; PCO2 45", "PO2 60; PCO2 40"],
    correctAnswer: "PO2 50; PCO2 60", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 95,
    question: "Which of the following is used to localize and treat renal calculi?",
    options: [
      "Extracorporeal shock wave lithotripsy",
      "Percutaneous nephrostography",
      "Magnetic resonance angiography",
      "Renal angiography",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Extracorporeal shock wave lithotripsy", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 96,
    question:
      "What condition refers to the inability of the heart to propel blood at a rate and volume sufficient to provide adequate supply to the tissues?",
    options: ["myocardial infarction", "congestive heart failure", "coronary artery disease", "left-to-right shunts"],
    correctAnswer: "congestive heart failure", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 97,
    question: "What is the radiographic appearance of duodenal ulcer?",
    options: ["cloverleaf", "rat-tail", "string sign", "linitis plastica pattern"],
    correctAnswer: "cloverleaf", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 98,
    question: "Cushing syndrome is a disorder of which structure?",
    options: ["thyroid gland", "adrenal gland", "hypothalamus", "pituitary gland"],
    correctAnswer: "adrenal gland", // 'b' = 1
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 99,
    question: "Which cranial nerve is the most common site for tumors of the peripheral nerve sheath?",
    options: ["4", "6", "7", "8"],
    correctAnswer: "8", // 'd' = 3
    rationale: "",
  },
  {
    id: 100,
    question: "Which of the following is responsible for the abnormally increased number of cells in tumors?",
    options: ["proliferation", "Differentiation", "prognosis", "Mitosis"],
    correctAnswer: "proliferation", // 'a' = 0
    rationale: "",
  },
];
